How does Yolo find a correct Bounding Box when it looks at an image broken up by grid?
当 YOLO 看到一个用网格划分的图像时 如何查找正确的边界框？
The trick is that it assigns the ground-truth bounding box for
诀窍在于它将图像中一个对象的真实边界框
one object in an image to only one grid cell in the training image.
仅分配给训练图像中的一个网格单元
So, only one grid cell is meant to locate the object.
因此只有一个网格单元会定位图像
Now, how is this grid cell chosen?
如何选择这个网格单元？
For each training image,
对于每个训练图像
we locate the midpoint of each object in the image and then we assign
我们找到图像中每个对象的中点 然后将真实边界框
the true bounding box to the grid cell that contains that midpoint. Let's see an example.
分配给包含该中点的网格单元 我们来看一个示例
In this image of a person,
在这个有人的图像中
we locate the midpoint of this person indicated by the yellow dot.
我们定位用黄色点表示的此人的中点
This dot contained by one grid cell,
这个点包含在一个网格单元中
so we assign the ground-truth bounding box to
因此我们将真实边界框仅分配给这个网格单元
this grid cell alone and the ground truth vector for
这个网格单元的正确标注
this grid cell which will be used for training will look like
看起来将这样 该向量将用于训练
this and even though this other grid cell also contains part of the person,
虽然另一个网格单元也包含此人的一部分
it's ground-truth vector will look like this.
但是它的正确标注将看起来这样
We treat it as if it does not contain an object and its PC value equal zero.
我们将其视作不包含对象 其 pc 值为 0
Now let's see how we determine the numerical values of X,
我们来看看如何确定 x y w 和 h 的值
Y, W, and H. In the Yolo algorithm,
在 YOLO 算法中
X and Y determine the coordinates of the center of the bounding box relative to
x 和 y 确定的是边界框
the grid cell and W and H determine
相对于网格单元的中心坐标
the width and the height of the box relative to the whole image.
w 和 h 确定的是边界框相对于整个图像的宽和高
The convention is that the upper left corner of a grid cell has
按惯例 网格单元的左上角坐标是 (0,0)
coordinates 0,0 or the bottom right hand corner has coordinates 1,1.
或者右下角的坐标是 (1,1)
So in this example,
因此 在这个示例中
the centre point relative to the grid cell coordinate system is
相对于网格单元坐标系的中心点为
X equal to about 0.5 and Y equal to 0.3.
X 约等于 0.5 y 等于 0.3
Now the width of the predicted bounding box W is
预测边界框的宽度 w 是 0.1
0.1 because its width is about 10 percent the width of
因为它的宽度大约是整个图像宽度的 10%
the entire image and the height H is
高度 h 是 0.4
0.4 because its height is about 40 percent the height of the entire image.
因为它的高度大约是整个图像高度的 40%
Notice that in this system,
注意 在这个体系中
all bounding box coordinate values fall between zero and one
所有边界框坐标值都在 0 和 1 之间
and the width and height of
边界框的宽度和高度
the bounding box can be bigger than the size of the grid cell.
可以大于网格单元的大小
This technique is very similar to normalization.
这个技巧和标准化非常相似
By standardizing the range of these values,
通过标准化这些值的范围
this algorithm becomes easier to train and converge to a smaller error.
这个算法变得更易于训练并收敛于更小的误差
But there's one problem with this method.
但是这个方法有一个问题
Imagine that a network has trained on a fine grid and
假设有个网络在细小的网格上接受训练
only one small grid cell has a true bounding box for an object in an image,
只有一个小的网格单元具有图像中对象的真实边界框
what do you think will happen once a network like
如果这样的网络看到具有对象的新测试图像
this sees a new test image with an object in it?
你认为会发生什么？